<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Joakim Wimmerstedt - Portfolio</title>
 <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2016-10-11T18:12:42+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Joakim Wimmerstedt</name>
   <email>joakim.wimmerstedt@hyperisland.se</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Laddkoll</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2016/09/01/laddkoll/"/>
   <updated>2016-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2016/09/01/laddkoll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.laddkoll.se/&quot;&gt;Laddkoll&lt;/a&gt; is a swedish startup making it easier for electrical vehicle owners to charge their cars. They do this by providing both a localization service so the user easily can find a charge point, and by providing a simple way for the user to pay for both the parking and the actual charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I &amp;ldquo;arrived at the scene&amp;rdquo;, there was two code bases to maintain. A native iOS version that worked really well and a less performant android version built on top on &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/react-native/&quot;&gt;React Native&lt;/a&gt;. The scope of the job was to refactor and improve the React Native version to such a degree that we could replace the iOS version with it. The motivation behind this was to lessen the amount of hours needed to maintain the both apps, and to streamline development since the Laddkoll team was small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the job we realized that React Native brought a whole lot more benefits than we usually thought. One of them was that it made it possible for services such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://microsoft.github.io/code-push/&quot;&gt;code-push&lt;/a&gt; to deliver updates to the app without going through App Store or Google Play Store. This is a major feature and makes it easy for a small team to get important bug fixes out, so we implemented it very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about the actual product, download it and try it out! It&amp;rsquo;s on &lt;a href=&quot;http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=se.laddkoll&quot;&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appstore.com/laddkoll&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first forage into the world of React Native and I&amp;rsquo;ve got to say that I&amp;rsquo;m impressed. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a couple of apps before, but this is by far the most pleasant developer experience I&amp;rsquo;ve had. The only problems I&amp;rsquo;ve run into is third party libraries that weren&amp;rsquo;t working properly, and I can&amp;rsquo;t really blame that on the RN team. I&amp;rsquo;m already using React Native for a couple of other projects and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to see where it is going next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/sp-enjoyment.mp4&quot; autoplay loop mute &gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My whole experience with react native summarized in one animation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>shhbostad.se</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2016/02/20/shhbostad/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2016/02/20/shhbostad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This autumn I spent some time with the newly founded agency &lt;a href=&quot;http://sebton.se/&quot;&gt;Sebton/Co&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re great little family run company &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The task&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main project I was brought in to develop was a new website for Svenska Hyreshus, a swedish property group. The website that was planned needed to solve a number of issues, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being easy for their managers to update themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being flexible in terms of layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporating their new system for building projects &lt;em&gt;(This was a big one!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being able to run on a hosting solution that only supports PHP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Choosing a platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a lot of research about the limitations around this new system of theirs, it was decided that the site would run on wordpress to keep development time down. Wordpress in itself encourages this &amp;ldquo;Plug &amp;amp; Play&amp;rdquo; mentality with a lot of random plugins. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a couple of sites being very hard to debug due to plugins being incompatible and I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to go down that route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led the highest priority of the initial development to be stability. I set out to list exactly what kind of plugins would be needed, and then to test them out to see if everything worked as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I decided to go with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.advancedcustomfields.com/pro/&quot;&gt;Advanced Custom Fields Pro&lt;/a&gt; for their flexible layouts and repeater fields, &lt;a href=&quot;https://yoast.com/wordpress/plugins/seo/&quot;&gt;Yoast SEO&lt;/a&gt; for easy SEO management and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org/plugins/wp-mail-smtp/&quot;&gt;WP Mail SMTP&lt;/a&gt; to allow wordpress to send mail via smtp. Othe plugins were discarded as they wheren&amp;rsquo;t needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bringing Wordpress to 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress, as I said, feels kind of outdated to me. It&amp;rsquo;s been around since forever and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel that the majority of the wordpress community embraces modern development tools. I wanted to make sure to do wordpress justice by trying out a better workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led me to try out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wesleytodd/YeoPress&quot;&gt;Yeopress&lt;/a&gt;, an unofficial yeoman generator for wordpress. It even has support for vagrant, which is awesome. I did however make some changes after trying it out, such as adding support for a staging environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Building the theme&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the theme, I went with the yeopress template theme as a base and built upon that. Grunt was used as the taskrunner, bower as the package manager and we used scss for styling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme needed to be very flexible in terms of layout, so we built it to rely heavily on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.advancedcustomfields.com/pro/&quot;&gt;Advanced Custom Fields&lt;/a&gt;. Their repeater- and flexible content-fields are a godsend - I really don&amp;rsquo;t think theres any other option. With a developer key it&amp;rsquo;s also very cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I recieved the first drafts on the design I started to break everything up in rows, like small lego pieces. From the wordpress admin one could easily go in, add a block (let&amp;rsquo;s say a Hero Module for example) and simply position it amongst the other blocks in whatever order they themselves fancied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fucking love &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.advancedcustomfields.com/pro/&quot;&gt;Advanced Custom Fields&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Adding support for Vitec&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the clients big demands was to have support for their new system for building projects, Vitec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitec is a great platform for what Svenska Hyreshus are doing. It&amp;rsquo;s something for both brokers, project managers and so on, but when you update a project the changes also push to the biggest housing sites in sweden, such as Hemnet or Blocket Bostad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bring this funcitonality to the new project I developed a custom plugin that fetched the information from Vitec&amp;rsquo;s SOAP API, stored them in our database and programmatically added pages for the current projects. Since we couldn&amp;rsquo;t use the &amp;lsquo;push&amp;rsquo; features that hemnet or blocket had to update the information instantly as it was updated in the system, I set up a CRON-job to fetch new information from Vitec every 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Final words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with how the site turned out. What we&amp;rsquo;ve got now is a very easily maintained little website that works well. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard from the clients they&amp;rsquo;re happy as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shhbostad.se&quot;&gt;Check out the website at shhbostad.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I'm going freelance!</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/articles/2015/07/06/im-going-freelance/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/articles/2015/07/06/im-going-freelance</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s finally decided. I&amp;rsquo;m going freelance in august. Being a web developer has never been more exciting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.giphy.com/media/Ap03lHKFHseNW/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Gif of craziness&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;ll look in august when I&amp;rsquo;m about to make the switch.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting more contracting requests than I can handle outside a regular job, so the natural step is to &lt;strong&gt;make it&lt;/strong&gt; my regular job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What services will you provide?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front End Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technological Audits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessibility Audits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SEO Audits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can help you out with loads of stuff, these being a few of them. I&amp;rsquo;d also be happy to help you out with technical advise for whatever project you have in mind. Sometimes you might just need someone to discuss your idea with to see if it&amp;rsquo;s good or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a big network of friends and colleagues if you need help with anything else in the digital production or digital strategy sphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why should I hire you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m good at what I do. Also because I&amp;rsquo;m great at teamwork, good at making informed decisions and I&amp;rsquo;m a hard worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Can you make &amp;lt;project&amp;gt; for us?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably. &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:joakim.wimmerstedt@hyperisland.com&quot;&gt;Send me a message&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;tel:+46723153420&quot;&gt;call me&lt;/a&gt; and tell me about the project and we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>GetSwish.se</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2015/07/02/getswish/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2015/07/02/getswish</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first project I got to do when I started at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theworldloves.com&quot;&gt;The World Loves&lt;/a&gt; in April 2014 was the website for Swish. Swish is the largest mobile payment provider in Sweden, with over 2 800 000 users (as of july 2015). That&amp;rsquo;s kind of a lot for a country that has under 10 million inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getswish.se&quot;&gt;GetSwish.se&lt;/a&gt; remains the largest website I&amp;rsquo;ve developed with over 180k visits each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/swish-carousel.mp4&quot; autoplay loop mute &gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The carousel was made with facebooks paper campaign site as inspiration. It&amp;rsquo;s not totally enjoyable in gif-form, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getswish.se&quot;&gt;check it out live&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/swish-counter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image displaying the counter&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The front page grid was made to feel alive, so each month we posted new statistics about Swish.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/swish-parallax.mp4&quot; autoplay loop mute &gt;&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We tried giving the image headers parallax effect so that the website wouldn&amp;rsquo;t feel to static on the subpages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website is running on wordpress. I was heavily invested in finding a CMS that did exactly what we needed it to, but in the end Wordpress was the best fit due to our experience with developing for it. The simplicity for administrators was also a big thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For easy development we were using git for versioning and grunt with sass(scss compass), htmlmin and require.js(with r.js) for packaging. Grunt would also detect changes to the images to see if they needed compression or in the case of svg&amp;rsquo;s, minification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to css grid, we actually used one I made myself just for that project. It&amp;rsquo;s a basic setup with adjustable columns and gutter width, written in scss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Optimization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the very content heavy first page we base64 encoded most of the imagery to load in more high res images as they were needed. This strategy allowed for a much quicker pageload, and created a natural evaluation point to check if we should feed the client a regular resolution image or a retina version of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scrolling performance was also a high priority during development, so all scroll listeners were throttled to 60fps and we made sure never to change values for javascript animated items when they were not in the viewport. Minimizing dom manipulations were a priority from day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site also featured the standard &amp;ldquo;run-of-the-mill&amp;rdquo; optimizations such as compression and minification of assets, gzip compression, varnish, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Deploys&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used git for all deploys. We had a grunt task set up for version tagging and automatically merging all the tagged commits to the release branch. We&amp;rsquo;d then ssh into the hosting server and simply run a git pull from the repository directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getswish.se&quot;&gt;Check out the website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Building Alchemist App</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/articles/2015/07/02/building-alchemist-app/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/articles/2015/07/02/building-alchemist-app</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In November 2014 we were experiencing a low activity period for the tech team over at The World Loves. Together with my colleague (and former classmate) &lt;a href=&quot;http://karlerikjonatan.github.io/&quot;&gt;Jonatan Pettersson&lt;/a&gt; I set out to learn something new. We decided to make an iOS app in Swift, mostly since neither of us had done one before and Swift was growing as a language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Introducing Alchemist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our idea was simple – we should start out as we started out with javascript. Making a product that simply wrapped open API&amp;rsquo;s and presented it&amp;rsquo;s information in a collected way. An aggregator, of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had recently started using an awesome service called &lt;a href=&quot;https://tastekid.com&quot;&gt;TasteKid&lt;/a&gt; that recommends media to a users liking. You post a title and get recommendations back. They just happened to have an open API so we decided to simply work around that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Constrained by constraints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confession time: I&amp;rsquo;ve never developed a GUI that didn&amp;rsquo;t rely on CSS and HTML before making this app, and I&amp;rsquo;ve still never tried flexbox in CSS. Constraints was a totally new concept for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I did get a hang for it pretty quickly though, mostly thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appcoda.com/introduction-auto-layout/&quot;&gt;this article over at appcoda.com&lt;/a&gt; and the video tutorials over at [Team Treehouse]. I&amp;rsquo;m still not convinced it&amp;rsquo;s the best way of specifying UI layouts, but then again – CSS is even more shit than this. I did miss the styling parts from CSS though. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;JSON is a bitch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, turns out we web developers are spoiled brats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating JSON is such a breeze in javascript that I&amp;rsquo;ve never given it any thought on how weird it can be in other languages. We spent the better part of a day together just trying to figure it out, and we ended up using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SwiftyJSON/SwiftyJSON&quot;&gt;SwiftJSON library&lt;/a&gt; because it made it so much easier. Our app was so reliant on JSON sources (themoviedb, goodreads, youtube, tastekid, etc.) that this was a major life saver. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned a lot and gained some valuable understanding on how different things are over in app-land. While iOS dev&amp;rsquo;s have stuff like CocoaPods, the tooling isn&amp;rsquo;t like the web development scene at all. It might be because everything is so controlled by Apple and that xCode in itself functions like a framework. While &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.github.io/react-native/&quot;&gt;React Native&lt;/a&gt; might change the environment somewhat it&amp;rsquo;s still going to be a bit lack-luster. I like to be able to choose what way I want to develop a product, but in iOS there&amp;rsquo;s mostly just one way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, Swift isn&amp;rsquo;t really harder than regular web front end technologies if you&amp;rsquo;re doing it at a basic level. Apple are literally giving you almost all the tools you need. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to make another app once I&amp;rsquo;ve got enough free time to try out React Native.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is available for download over at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=942473452&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;app store&lt;/a&gt; if you want to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wonder World Fur</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2015/07/01/wonder-world-fur/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2015/07/01/wonder-world-fur</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During my internship at Stink Digital back in late 2012 I was part of the two man developer team who built the Wonder World Fur campaign site for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wwf.org/&quot;&gt;World Wildlife Foundation&lt;/a&gt;(WWF). Wonder World Fur was a brand where WWF sold furs from 100% imaginary animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our team consisted of &lt;a href=&quot;http://ianmadethis.com/&quot;&gt;Ian Hart&lt;/a&gt; and me from the London office and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.charlie-montagut.com/&quot;&gt;Charlie Montagut&lt;/a&gt; from the then newly opened Paris office. I was in charge of most of the front-end. The Project was awarded with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefwa.com/site/wonder-world-fur&quot;&gt;FWA SOTD award in April 2013&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/wwf-video.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wonder World Fur utilized autoplaying fullscreen videos.&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The site in itself used autoplaying fullscreen videos. These ranged from subtle cinemagraphs to the campaign trailer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/wwf-grid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wonder World Fur used a grid to let imagery speak instead of text.&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The site also featured some very balanced animations for entry and hover effects to highlight the imagery and the products. These can&amp;rsquo;t be showcased propperly since no screen recordings from when the site was up has been saved.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/wwf-info.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Each of the imaginary animals had information panels where you could learn more about them&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Each of the imaginary animals had information panels where you could learn more about them. You could watch a 3D-rendered video to see what they would look like in action, listen to the different sounds the animal could make or just read a description.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site has sadly gone off the web since it was online, but you could still see it it&amp;rsquo;s FWA award: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefwa.com/site/wonder-world-fur&quot;&gt;http://www.thefwa.com/site/wonder-world-fur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mabi.se</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2015/06/30/mabi/"/>
   <updated>2015-06-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/cases/2015/06/30/mabi</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first live project using Angular.js was the website for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mabi.se&quot;&gt;Mabi&lt;/a&gt;, one of the top rental car companies in Sweden. It was the biggest assignments I had over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.river.se&quot;&gt;River&lt;/a&gt; apart from a iAd campaign I did for Nike. I was the sole front end developer on this project, but some advanced features like figuring out the rules for the car filtration was definitely a team effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/mabi-landing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the landing page.&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mabi had a lot of good imagery the designers could blow up for the banners.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/mabi-cars.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the cars section inside the booking flow.&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The car filtration is where I definitely learned the most about directives as components, how ng-reapeats work as well as the limitations of angular.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/mabi-offices.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the offices page.&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A customized google map that shows the closest rental spots was also a fun and quick exersice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site&amp;rsquo;s changed a lot since I left River in early 2014, but if you still want to check it out, just go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mabi.se&quot;&gt;Mabi.se.&lt;/a&gt;. A heads up though – it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like there&amp;rsquo;s support for higher resolutions than 1080p any more, so the background image is ugly if you&amp;rsquo;re on a big screen.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>About Joakim</title>
   <link href="http://cupofjoakim.github.io/articles/1991/07/24/about-me/"/>
   <updated>1991-07-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://cupofjoakim.github.io/articles/1991/07/24/about-me</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cupofjoakim.github.io/assets/images/post-images/me.png&quot; alt=&quot;It&amp;#39;s Joakim, in space!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joakim Wimmerstedt is a self thaught web developer currently trying to solve parking problems at Parkando Technologies. In the past he&amp;rsquo;s worked in advertising, creating websites for companies big and small, such as WWF, Swish, SHHBostad, Nike and Samsung. A full CV is available over at &lt;a href=&quot;linkedin&quot;&gt;linkedin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also brews beer and goes to festivals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of brewed batches: 12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of festivals attended: 31&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
